<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ucb | ]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io/blog/categories/ucb/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-06T23:11:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidtingsu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Su]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracking Cal Events]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io/blog/2014/04/06/tracking-cal-events/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-06T21:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidtingsu.github.io/blog/2014/04/06/tracking-cal-events</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Integrate with Google Calendar</h3>

<p>Using a calendaring system is tied with productivity hacking as discussed in <a href="http://www.jamesmaa.com/2012/12/02/james-maas-productivity-hacking-guide/is">James Maa&rsquo;s productivity hacking</a>. I first discovered that it is possible to embed calendars and my class schedule into my google calendar after using <a href="http://ninjacourses.com/">NinjaCourses</a>. A public calendar in ics or ical format can be imported into Google calendar by following <a href="https://support.google.com/calendar/answer/37100?hl">these steps</a>. Take, for example <a href="http://ninjacourses.com/schedule/view/40957/?t=567b9877">my  freshman fall 2010 schedule</a> which can be viewed in <a href="http://ninjacourses.com/schedule/view/40957/?t=567b9877">html</a>. For schedulebuilder users, because <a href="https://schedulebuilder.berkeley.edu/">schedulebuilder</a> uses virtually the same technology as ninja courses, you can import the events from link titled &ldquo;Download ICal&rdquo; on the &ldquo;Saved Schedules&rdquo; page.</p>

<p>Besides incorporating my class schedule into my calendar, I also import into my Google Calendar:</p>

<h4>UC Berkeley Academic Calendar</h4>

<p>The calendar url to embed into google calendar <a href="">webcal://registrar.berkeley.edu/UCBAcadCal.ics</a> and you can find other formats <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/CalendarDisp.aspx?terms=current">here</a>. You will always know when school starts and when there is break, but  make sure to take note of Add/Drop deadlines and P/NP Change of Grade Option deadlines which are not part of the calendar.</p>

<h4>Facebook Events</h4>

<p>I follow <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/152652248136178/"> these steps</a>.</p>

<h4>Department Events</h4>

<p>I keep track of department events to find infosessions, undergraduate social hours, and seminars. After reading the <a href="http://events.berkeley.edu/documentation/user/rss.html">documentation</a>  for exporting calendar events I was able to use <a href="http://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/ical/sn/eecs/type/month.htm">http://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/ical/sn/eecs/type/month.htm</a> as the embed url for EECS department sponsored events. To make sure that I also cover other non-department sponsored events, I also follow the facebook events of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ieeeucb">IEEE</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/CalBlueprint">Blueprint</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/csuahosers/">CSUA</a>, and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/hackberkeley/">Hackers@Berkeley</a>. View a list of other <a href="http://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/?view=other_calendars">campus calendars</a>. For all of the calendar listed under UC Berkeley Calendar network, just reformat the url to be <a href="http://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/ical/sn/">http://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/ical/sn/</a>&lt;deparment-name>/type/month.htm.  I encourage you to dig around and search for calendar urls on the linked pages. For those of you particularly inclined in the visual and performing arts, consider <a href="http://www.calperformances.org/2013-14.ics">Cal Performances</a> and <a href="webcal://press.bampfa.berkeley.edu/calendar/BAM-PFA.ics"> BAM/PFA</a>.</p>

<h3>Unsupported</h3>

<h4>Career Center events</h4>

<p>You can find a list of <a href="http://career.berkeley.edu">Cal Career Center</a> events (workshops and career centers)
<a href="https://berkeley-csm.symplicity.com/calendar/index.php?ss=ical_agenda&_ksl=1&s=">here</a>, but the bottleneck is that you have  download each of the events individually and there is currently know easy way to import the list of career center events into Google Calendar.</p>

<h3>Additional Resources:</h3>

<p><a href="https://support.google.com/calendar/answer/37100?hl=en">Subscribe to public calendars using the calendar address</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
